ILGWU Legal Department Audio-Visual Materials 5780/107 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Legal Department Audio-Visual Materials
1965-1980
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Siems, Frederick Rolle
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/107 AV
1.47 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
The collection contains audio recordings of interviews with ILGWU members relating to working at, and, later, striking against the Kellwood Company, as well as notes relating to these interviews.
6849843
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 25, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
From very early on in its existence, the ILGWU had need for legal counsel, and this was handled in the union's main offices in cooperation with hired attorneys. As the union grew and especially after the passage of the Taft-Hartley Act in 1947, the union found cause to establish a Legal Department. The department provided general legal counsel to the union and its affiliates, worked to develop collective bargaining agreement terms, and represented the ILGWU in litigation and arbitration. After the formation of the Master Agreements Department in 1965, the responsibilities for developing CBA terms shifted to the new department.
Scope and Contents
The Legal Department records do not comprehensively document the ILGWU legal activities, instead focusing on specific cases or series of cases.
Two ILGWU cases are documented in the Legal Department records. The first case involved the Kellwood Corporation, and the second involved the Donnelly Garment Company. The records relating to the Kellwood case (5780/107, 5780/107 AV, 5780/107 P) include court documents, correspondence and memoranda, surveys of strikers, organizing leaflets and newsletters (from both the union and the company), Steve Honeyman's draft accounts of the strike, audio and transcripts of Honeyman's interviews with ILGWU members and staff, newspaper clippings, photographs, and other printed material. The Donnelly Garment Company's case against the ILGWU is documented primarily through transcripts of the case, legal briefs, and related court documents.
Records on series of cases are the most general and extensive of the Legal Department records. They include records on ILGWU cases in the U.S. courts (5780/081), records documenting cases before the National War Labor Board (5780/085), and records relating to a wide variety contract negotiations, arbitration proceedings, and courts cases (5780/063).
Researchers may find complementary material in the other parts of the ILGWU records, such as the papers of the international leadership, especially the papers of ILGWU presidents (Series IV); the records of local unions in instances where these affiliates were involved in litigation or arbitration (Series III); and the collective bargaining agreements (Series VI). Related collections at the Kheel Center include decisions of the Coat and Suit Industry's Impartial Chairman (6036/015) and decisions of the Dress Industry's Impartial Chairman (6036/017).
For the AV collection, included are audio recordings of interviews with ILGWU members relating to working at, and, later, striking against the Kellwood Company, as well as notes relating to these interviews. Also included are several tapes on sweatshops, some of which feature Frederick Siems.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/107: ILGWU Legal Department Records 5780/107 P: ILGWU Legal Department Photographs 5780/081: ILGWU Legal Department Records 5780/063: ILGWU Legal Department Records 5780/162: ILGWU Legal Department Donnelly Garment Company v. ILGWU Records
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; Siems, Frederick Rolle, 1915-; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Legal Dept.
6849843
- Movie Duplicate Film, 1 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 2 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 3 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 4 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 5 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 6 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 7 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 8 (Box 1)
- Movie Duplicate Film, 9 (Box 1)
- Bolden, Mary [interview], 1 (Box 2)
- Bolden, Mary [interview], 2 (Box 2)
- Bulison, Nellie [interview], 3 (Box 2)
- Cato, B.C. [interview], 4 (Box 2)
- Clay, Glenn [interview], 6 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  2 copies
- Clay, Glenn [interview], 7 (Box 2)
  copy
- Daniels, Jessie [interview], 8 (Box 2)
- Daniels, Ora [interview], 9 (Box 2)
  part 1
- Daniels, Ora [interview], 10 (Box 2)
  part 2
- Daniels, Ora [interview], 11 (Box 2)
  part 3
- Glenn, Ida [interview], 12 (Box 2)
- Hanby, Ocyleue [interview], 13 (Box 2)
- Jackson, Jerry Sue [interview], 14 (Box 2)
- Jefferson, Bobby [interview], 15 (Box 2)
- Lacey, Jack [interview], 16 (Box 2)
- Lacey, Jack [interview], 17 (Box 2)
- Luop, Alice [interview], 18 (Box 2)
- Martin, Art [interview], 19 (Box 2)
- Webster, Lew [interview], 20 (Box 2)
- Martin, Art [interview], 20 (Box 2)
- Martin, Eldora [interview[, 21 (Box 2)
- Perlstein, Jerry [interview], 22 (Box 2)
- Perlstein, Jerry [interview], 23 (Box 2)
- Quiggle, Richard [interview], 24 (Box 2)
- Quiggle, Richard [interview], 25 (Box 2)
- Roberts, Florence [interview], 26 (Box 2)
- Rodgers, Alberta [interview], 28 (Box 2)
- Siems, Fred [interview], 30 (Box 2)
- Siems, Fred [interview], 31 (Box 2)
- Siems, Fred [interview], 32 (Box 2)
- Siems, Fred [interview], 33 (Box 2)
  part 4
- Siems, Fred [interview], 34 (Box 2)
  part 5
- Siems, Fred [interview], 35 (Box 2)
  part 6
- Wilson, Delores Jean [interview], 36 (Box 2)
- Wilson, Delores Jean [interview], 37 (Box 2)
- Youngdahl, James Edward [interview], 38 (Box 2)
- Youngdahl, James Edward [interview], 39 (Box 2)
- Youngdahl, James Edward [interview], 40 (Box 2)
- Youngdahl, James Edward [interview], 41 (Box 2)
- Youngdahl, James Edward [interview], 42 (Box 2)
- Executive Board Panel Discussion, 43 (Box 2)
  August 3
- Horizons #800319, Sweatshops in New York, 1980; 44 (Box 2)
- Tape 8, 45 (Box 2)
- Attention New York, WABC-radio, Fred Sims [Siems] from the ILGWU, 1979; 46 (Box 2)
  September 30
- NBC Metropolitan Report, Fried Siems, "Sweatshops", 1979; 47 (Box 2)
  August 30
- WOR, 48 (Box 2)
- WNBC Metropolitan Report, Fred Simms [Siems] of ILGWU, 49 (Box 2)
  September 2; 8:00 a.m.
- Mary Bolden, 1 (Box 3)
  Master Copy. 2 Discs
- Nellie Burlison, 2 (Box 3)
  Master Copy. 1 Disc
- B.C. Cato, 3 (Box 3)
- Glenn Clay, 4 (Box 3)
  Master Copy. 3 Discs
- Jessie Daniels, 5 (Box 3)
- Ora Daniels, 6 (Box 3)
- Ida Glenn, 7 (Box 3)
- Ocyleve Hanby, 8 (Box 3)
- Jerry Sue Jackson, 9 (Box 3)
- Bobby Jefferson, 10 (Box 3)
- Jack Lacey, 11 (Box 3)
- Alice Lupo, 12 (Box 3)
- Art Martin, 13 (Box 3)
- Eldora Martin, 14 (Box 3)
- Jerry Perlstein, 15 (Box 3)
- Richard Quiggle, 16 (Box 3)
- Florence Roberts, 17 (Box 3)
- Alberto Rodgers, 18 (Box 3)
- Fred Siems, 19 (Box 3)
  Master Copy. 6 Discs
- Lew Webster, 20 (Box 3)
- Delores Jean Wilson, 21 (Box 3)
- James Edward Youngdahl, 22 (Box 3)
- Executive Board, 23 (Box 3)
- Horizons, 24 (Box 3)
- Tape 8, 25 (Box 3)
- WABC, 26 (Box 3)
- NBC, 27 (Box 3)
- WOR, 28 (Box 3)
- WNBC, 29 (Box 3)
- Mary Bolden, 1 (Box 4)
  2 Discs
- Nellie Buelison, 2 (Box 4)
  1 Disc
- B.C. Cato, 3 (Box 4)
- Glenn Clay, 4 (Box 4)
  3 Discs
- Jessie Daniels, 5 (Box 4)
- Ora Daniels, 6 (Box 4)
- Ida Glenn, 7 (Box 4)
- Ocyleve Hanby, 8 (Box 4)
- Jerry Sue Jackson, 9 (Box 4)
- Bobby Jefferson, 10 (Box 4)
- Jack Lacey, 11 (Box 4)
- Alice Lupo, 12 (Box 4)
- Art Martin, 13 (Box 4)
- Eldora Martin, 14 (Box 4)
- Jerry Perlstein, 15 (Box 4)
- Richard Quiggle, 16 (Box 4)
- Florence Roberts, 17 (Box 4)
- Alberta Rodgers, 18 (Box 4)
- Fred Siems, 19 (Box 4)
  6 Discs
- Lew Webster, 20 (Box 4)
- Delores Jean Williams, 21 (Box 4)
- James Edward Youngdahl, 22 (Box 4)
- Executive Board, 23 (Box 4)
- Horizons, 24 (Box 4)
- Tape 8, 25 (Box 4)
- WABC, 26 (Box 4)
- NBC, 27 (Box 4)
- WOR, 28 (Box 4)
- WNBC, 29 (Box 4)
- Mary Bolden, 1966; 1 (Box 5)
- Nellie Burlison, 2 (Box 5)
  August 2
- B.C. Cato, 3 (Box 5)
  August 12
- Geneva Childs, 1966; 4 (Box 5)
- Glenn Clay, 5 (Box 5)
  November 4
- Ora Daniels, 6 (Box 5)
- Ocyleve Hanby, 1965; 7 (Box 5)
- Jessie Daniels, 1965; 8 (Box 5)
- Ida Glenn, 9 (Box 5)
- Jerry Sue Jackson, 10 (Box 5)
  August 15; News Clipping Included
- Bobby Jefferson, 11 (Box 5)
  August 17
- Jack Lacey, 12 (Box 5)
  August 28
- Alice Lupo, 13 (Box 5)
  August 4
- Art Martin, 1973; 14 (Box 5)
  August 21
- Eldora Martin, 15 (Box 5)
  August 18
- Jerry Perlstein, 1977; 16 (Box 5)
  January 15
- Richard F. Quiggle, 1974; 17 (Box 5)
- Ross Roberts, 18 (Box 5)
  July 2
- Alberta Rodgers, 1967; 19 (Box 5)
  September 10
- Fred Siems, 20 (Box 5)
  September 2
- Delores Jean Wilson, 21 (Box 5)
  August 23
- James Edward Youngdahl, 22 (Box 5)
- Executive Board Discussion, 23 (Box 5)
- Notes On Audio Transfer, 24 (Box 5)
- Audio digitized from the collection. (Box 6)